long day today so I'm gonna make the
video now this morning for taking my kid
to school now today I feel feel
overwhelmed I feel watching the videos
yesterday about the their name is
eluding me minam are people who were
having genocide committed against them
and they're not the only ones on the
globe at the moment having genocide
committed it annoys me that like that
definition it takes us so long to even
define anything is that so define it is
that first and then you can go back and
undefined it like this isn't a rape
charge this is the international
community needs to be doing something
and the international community I think
means us not our governments there needs
to be a way when we hear of an
international crisis that that moves us
that we're called to do something about
there's an easy way to do it we need a
social media platform that's designed
for social change where I'm not just
changing my profile picture but their
flag and hey we stand with whichever
country just got a terrorist attack
today I want to know that one there's an
actual coordinated effort to help I
don't know what we would do as citizens
in the case of genocide but with a
product app we don't need the UN to move
or whoever move to say they're gonna
start sanctions against that country we
can start them that day we the people
can say you know what I'm not I'm not
buying anything that was ever touched by
your country until you solve that
because murdering and displacing humans
is not a solution not if you want to be
a thriving a thriving person and also in
the shower this morning having this
thought of well I mean communism has
done some horrible has had some horrible
things done in it
on this planet I also just watched
Angelina Jolie I didn't know she was one
who is responsible for the movie but
about the Cambodia The Killing Fields
and it's told you good it's they killed
my father first or they came for my
father first know that I was killed in
the title also what's going on right now
in my tomorrow by the Buddhists which I
don't know why what effect but like the
Buddhists they're committing acts of
genocide I know it's not their first
time it's not but seriously there was
hope for any religious group how was the
one and there's no like it just happens
and we the people need to stand stronger
and all I did was watch like thing after
thing after thing they're like refugee
they're like living in camps in meinem
are but then they I don't know how they
escaped from there and go to Bangladesh
and how do our people think they're just
ridiculous we need a better way to one
just you know the truth that every
broadcast doesn't need to say okay like
you can't just spin the truth for your
broadcast so having a way to know like
how long have those people lived there
where are they from where are they and
whether that gives them any any claim to
anything like every human born on this
planet needs a place to be and in Canada
that's reflected in our treatment
reconciliation that like there is no
place for most of us to go to like I'm
Canadian this is my soil this is but it
was also stolen partly from some of my
ancestors but actually isn't that was
kind of stolen for my ancestors and so I
don't know just everything all at the
same time but I also see solutions and
feeling the burden of trying to get my
ideas out there fast enough to not feel
responsible for every genocide and
hurricane and he's to feel like there's
something we can do when something like
that happens it clearly in the
Hurricanes I mean
I think the difference in this hurricane
versus the Katrina hurricane is that
people weren't just waiting for the
government to take action people were
out in their boats saving people because
they realized the Coast Guard and Army
weren't gonna be there in time it takes
bureaucracy so long to act whereas we
can act the day the day it happens we
can act until until you stop this
genocide like we're not buying a product
I don't even know what do we buy from a
tomorrow what did they what do they get
what do they export what did they import
because you're also you know as the
owners of companies could say I'm not
going to sell to you but as consumers we
can say we're not going to buy from you
and that can be instant but updates your
app right like that's an action we can
take that has a meaning in the real
world we can mobilize resources once
there is a migration of mass people and
they have that they're living in refugee
counts like we can set up camps that
make more sense with their help people
who live there like Waste Systems that
make sense and food distribution and
schools and medical clinics and not have
it reliant people are giving Bangladesh
a hard time that they're not like
opening their doors to the mind of ours
they are their people but also whether
or not they're their people they're
humans and they need to have a place to
be but like Bangladesh can't take on
that no he needs of I just said billions
millions or tens hundreds of thousands
of people without help from the rest of
the world that's ridiculous and every
country is gonna have that every country
is gonna like we are closed we closed
down our borders to the like few
thousand they're able to like get work
with one of green cards are here be able
to come into the country and may give
bangladesh a hard time I don't know
we need a way to show her humanity more
easily to help cuz if I was that I would
feel like society abandoned me and that
replays itself again and again in
history would anyone care if we got
bombed we had an earthquake if we had
and chances are they would were white
rich country on white we're not always
your Canada I don't know I just have to
keep moving forward every day and
speaking my truth I just I don't I don't
know what to do to move this project
forward faster so it can save more lives